hey everyone welcome back to this Tosca
automation playlist and we are still
talking about the top 10 Tosca best
practices
now prior to this we have already spoken
about six best practices so if you have
not watched them I would recommend you
to go back to the playlist and watch all
of these videos before we continue with
this particular video
now before we go ahead and talk about
this best practice number seven I would
recommend you to also subscribe to our
channel so that you don't miss out on
the upcoming videos on this very topic
and coming to this particular best
practice transcendus recommends that you
use folders for test steps
so what does it mean we have already
seen this in number of different
examples but our test steps should be
grouped into different folders
not only this makes it more readable but
the debugging also is pretty easy which
leads to easier maintenance
now we'll see with an example how this
particular folder structure looks like
for an actual test case and what if you
don't use the folders right so all the
test steps could be under one test case
or even one folder okay so let's look at
an example and then maybe we can
understand this uh much better right
so coming back to Tosca I am now going
back to this particular test case for
demo webshop where we have automated
this for confirming the order right and
this is the test case name
and then when I open this you will see
there are three folders okay
preprocessing processing and post
processing now this is also one of the
best practices you should have at least
three main folders for your test case
one is the pre-processing which will
have all the prerequisite steps right
and then the processing which will
contain the actual test case scenarios
and then the post processing which is
basically any cleanup you want to do or
log out right so these kind of steps
will be contained inside processing
right pre-processing could be just
opening the URL or log into the website
right
and then inside processing so that's the
main folder inside this you will see
there are lots of other folders now this
could be divided based on the page of
the application or the functionality or
the steps of your test case so you can
do this any way you like but there
should be a certain structure right and
you should build folders for steps which
belong to at least one functionality or
maybe one page of the application
so for example here I have grouped my
registration uh scenario right inside
one folder
and then all the steps related to
registering a user are contained inside
this folder right similarly for login
user for product add products to cart
and then uh going to the shopping cart
checking out
filling all these details like billing
shipping address shipping method right
for confirming the order and then
verifying the PDF order information
right
now you can also make more folders as
you like inside the folder you can Again
mix up folders like here you can see
this is a repetition folder right so
that's why I've kept it inside another
folder I have submit condition
and if your test steps are getting too
lengthy or there are more test steps you
can basically create more folders right
in order to create a folder it's very
simple just right click and just create
a folder and then group your test steps
logically okay the advantage of this you
can see here it looks much better it is
much readable for any particular person
who is trying to view your test case he
can easily make out what is going on in
this test case and what is the test case
flow which the steps are inside which
folder right
the other advantage of this is uh while
we execute this okay or we are running
different executions if something fails
in some step right and we navigate from
the execution list to our test case we
can easily make out right looking at the
test step which particular functionality
it is linked to looking at the folder
name so if I got an error or some some
problem right during registration I can
directly come here and then I can modify
my steps right so basically I can fix my
tests more easily and much faster if you
have a structure like this right and
your test steps are grouped into
different folders
if you have something like this okay
here you can see all the test steps are
inside just a test case so there is no
folder structure right
now if something fails I need to go
through each test step and try to find
out uh which particular the step is
failing right also it doesn't look
readable right uh there is no uh test
case flow here and uh even we don't even
know
um like where we are logging into the
website where we are going into the
shopping cart where we are adding the
books right where we are checking out
which checkout exactly right so it's not
readable uh for a newcomer or any other
person who is trying to work in this
particular test case right so keeping in
mind that you will be working in a team
and there will be other team members who
will be referring to your test cases it
is always a best idea to create
different folders and then logically
group your test steps into each folder
okay
so that's the best practice which is
recommended by presenters and you should
be following it if you are working on a
real project with
a number of test cases which has got
lots of different test steps better to
group them into folders
so that's all for this video I hope you
enjoyed it and do leave any comments if
you have any questions on this
particular best practice we have lots
more videos coming up so keep watching
and keep learning